# michelle stermitz

Full-Stack Software Developer

Creator, collaborator and inquisitive logic-enthusiast with experience building engaging apps using technologies ranging from postgreSQL to React.

Portland, OR

**3**10.740.4913

michellestermitz.com

stermitzm@gmail.com

**in** in/michellestermitz michmitz /

#### Skills

Languages

## **Projects**

# AMAzine | Github, Website | React, PostgreSQL, Python (PRAW), Node.js

AMAzine is a web-magazine that scrapes interviews from Reddit's "Ask Me Anything" subreddit, as well as recipes and a photo of the day from multiple APIs. AMAzine was built in a week-long sprint using Python, Node and PostgreSQL. I wrote all but one of our eight API calls, custom hooks and services on both the front and back end. I also heavily contributed to the functionality of our components and styled the Thread Details page.

## Terminus | Github | PostgreSQL, Node.js, Inquirer, Express

To install, run command npx-terminus-game in terminal (Node required)

Terminus is a fun, Halloween-themed choose-your-own-adventure game playable in your terminal. Built in a week-long sprint with a team of six, Terminus utilizes Inquirer, Node.js, PostgreSQL, SuperAgent, Chalk, and Heroku. I heavily contributed to debugging, troubleshooting, and wiring Inquirer to deliver this thrilling experience to the user.

#### Truly Trivial | Github, Website | PostgreSQL, React, Node.js

Truly Trivial is a full-stack app that makes use of The Open Trivia DB to bring you a vintage gameshow experience! Featuring the spinning face of Bob Barker and the ability to bet on questions, you can either get rich or suffer the (satirical) consequences. Truly Trivial was built in a week-long sprint with a team of four and utilizes JavaScript, React, and CSS. I contributed to state management,, using React with JavaScript to manage bets, user choices and quiz results.

## FungusAmongUs | Github, Website | HTML, CSS, JavaScript

FungusAmongUs is an interactive, educational app that allows users to select a geographical region of Oregon and learn more about the mushrooms commonly found in that region. The user can then opt to "collect" that mushroom and add it to their mushroom basket for reference later. FungusAmongUs was built in a four day sprint with JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. I navigated the setup of our JavaScript functions to render the mushrooms on each page.

## **Career Highlights**

## Inventory Generalist | Powell's City of Books | 2019 - 2020

As an inventory generalist promoted from seasonal generalist, I proactively engaged with customers to ensure the best possible experience. Frequently communicated with other employees to maintain strict inventory standards.

## Freelance Graphic Design, Marketing, and Personal Assisting | 2017 - 2019

Upheld mission of professional brands via graphic design, Wordpress editing, keyword mapping and other tasks. Expanded skillset in accordance with business needs and sought feedback in order to deliver high quality product.

#### Manager, Graphic Designer | The Stensrud Playhouse | 2013 - 2017

As co-founder of this entertainment venue, I delivered successful marketing plans resulting in sold-out shows. Strengthened relationship with community by developing a large social media following and user-friendly website. Promoted company efficiency while managing sales, kitchen, and numerous employees.

## Awards

#### PDX WIT Scholarship | 2020 | Website

The purpose of PDXWIT is to encourage and empower those who identify as women, non-binary and underrepresented to join and stay in tech.

#### Education

### **Alchemy Code Lab** Portland, OR 2020

800+ hour full-stack software development program. JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, and PostgreSQL with an emphasis on test driven development and collaboration.

## Santa Monica College Santa Monica, CA 2010 - 2011

Explored different studies including anthropology, art, music, and interior design.

## HTML

JavaScript **CSS** 

#### **Backend**

**Express** Node.js Sequelize Redis **AWS** PRAW (Python) bcrypt

## **Frontend**

React Inquirer Redux

#### **Databases**

PostgreSQL/SQL

#### **Testing**

Jest Supertest QUnit

## **Tools & Services**

Git/GitHub Netlify Heroku Postman Adobe Photoshop Adobe Ilustrator Canva

## **University of Canterbury** Christchurch, NZ 2010

Double majored in anthropology and Chinese studies (Mandarin).